# Erik Rodriguez

Software Engineer

Location
Hemet, California
Email
perhapserik@gmail.com
LinkTree

linktr.ee/perhapserik ✓

Objective

Currently breaking into the industry. I strive in a fast-paced work environment and tend to gravitate to smaller diverse tight-knit teams that are driven to make an impact. I am a team player who is more than capable of communicating with cross-functional teams and experienced in designing, developing, debugging, and testing applications.

Skills

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, LESS/SASS, React, Redux, Node, Express, SQLite, Postman, Python, AWS, Netlify, Heroku, Vercel

**Projects** 

# Juicy ∕¹

React | CSS | Greensock | Figma

### A responsive marketing page that achieves a high audit score with animations

- Learned and utilized an animation library to eliminate time spent in continued support for animations across browsers and media platforms
- Inspected web application through repeated Chrome Lighthouse audit reports to identify opportunities for improvement in performance, accessibility, and search engine optimization

#### Anime Archive ✓

React | CSS | GraphQL | Trello | Figma

A mobile, web-based, online database of information related to anime

- Aided in designing a modern, user-friendly mobile web application using Figma
- Balanced workload of managing tasks and researching to communicate to an open source GraphQL API for data requests
- Applied reusable components throughout the application to minimize and simplify code maintenance

#### SignLingo **/**¹

React | Redux | SASS | Node | AWS | Trello

A mobile-first web application where users learn sign language through gamification

- Worked on a remote team of 6 (1 UX/UI, 5 Devs) over 8 weeks
- Built to the specifications of the stakeholder, delivering a mobile web app with learning model and gamified lessons
- Owned Redux implementation from creating store, action creators, reducers, and maintained all state data across the web app.
- Integrated Code Climate tool into the repository to ensure quality of code

#### 

HTML | LESS | GitHub Pages

A web application that helps patients find the right strains, dosing, intake method/ schedule

- Lead designer on the marketing web page aimed to brief users of our features
- Deployed landing page using Github pages to serve independently from the Front End

Experience

Lambda | Remote

Apr 2020 - May 2020

#### Labs Apprenticeship

• Participated in Lambda Labs Apprenticeship, where I contributed in remote teams to a real-world project called SignLingo. Three teams pushed SignLingo from idea to reality. Link to submitted video presentation ✓

StockX | Self Employed, Remote

Jan 2017 - Dec 2020

## Reseller

• Sold brand-name men's clothing, hard-to-find sneakers, art, and accessories

- Researched and analyzed markets to target products that return maximum results
- Serviced customers inquiring about the availability of items, sizing of products, or status of orders

US Army | Fort Campbell, Kentucky

Aug 2015 - Jan 2017

#### Infantryman

- Prepared mentally/physically for extreme environments and combat
- Diagnosed company humvees through monthly checks in order to minimize maintenance and reduce operations cost for the military
- Collaborated with a team of 19 to construct a bunker, task was completed 7 days ahead of schedule

Education

Lambda School | Remote

Dec 2019 - Oct 2020

## Full Stack Web Development & Computer Science /

• Lambda School is a 9 month accelerated program with an immersive (full-time, 40+ hours/week) hands-on curriculum with a focus on computer science, software engineering, and web development

US Army Military Training | Fort Benning, Georgia

Aug 2015 - Nov 2015

## Infantry School

• Trained for 14 weeks via One Station Unit Training, which includes Basic Combat Training and Advanced Individual Training, with a heavy emphasis on working as a team, performing well under stress, the willingness to accept challenges, and getting physically/mentally in shape.